Guide to the Frank Schonfeld Papers WAG.027
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series V: District Council 9 Trusteeship Records, 1966-1991
  - Trusteeship: Transcript of Hearing (2 of 3), 1977 June 16 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Trusteeship: Transcript of Hearing (3 of 3), 1977 June 16 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Trusteeship: Transcript of Hearing, 1977 June 20 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Trusteeship, 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Exhibits: F. Schonfeld, Trusteeship (Hearings), 1977 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Documents of F. Schonfeld, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Trusteeship (Damery): DC 9, 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Series VI: Litigation Records, 1960-1990
  Includes the Santos-Woodfinishers case, a jurisdictional fight with the Carpenters, and corrupt practices of District Council 9 leaders involving the transfer of work and jurisdiction of their own membership to competing unions in return for favors. Applications for wiretaps and progress reports issued to the court provide a wealth of information on corruption within DC 9. Additional materials, including press releases and rank-and-file flyers, reflect the complex course of events within DC 9 that landed it in the courts.
  - Santos, F. v. Bonanno, et. al. - Local 1011 (B. Hall), 1966 June 22 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - U. S. Court. of Appeals: Santos et. al (Wood Finishers v. Carpenters), 1976 March 11 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Santos, F. et. al. v. DC of Carpenters (Mario Vozzo) U.S. Court of Appeals, 1977 January 3 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Santos v. Carpenters (75 Ci v. 4355), pp. 1-215, 1979 April 9 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Santos v. Carpenters, pp. 216-299, 1979 April 10 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Santos v. Carpenters, pp. 300-472, 1979 April 1 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Santos v. Carpenters, pp. 473-636, 1979 April 16 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Santos v. Carpenters, pp. 637-778, 1979 April 17 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Supreme Court, NY State: Application, Affidavits for Wiretapping, 1989 May 18 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Supreme Court, NY State: Progress Reports (1st, 2nd, 3rd), 1989 May 18, 1989 June 1 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Supreme Court, NY State: Application, Affidavits for Wiretapping, 1989 June 7-1989 June 22 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Supreme Court, NY State: 7th, 9th, 10th Progress Reports, etc., 1989 June 6-1989 July 16 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Supreme Court, NY State: Application for Wiretapping, 1989 August 2-1989 August 24 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Supreme Court, NY State: Application for Wiretapping; 17th-19th Progress Repts., 1989 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Supreme Court, NY State: Application for Wiretaps; Progress Reports - #21-23, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Supreme Court, NY State: Application for Wiretap; 25th Progress Report, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Supreme Court, NY State: 26th Progress Report; etc., 1989 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Supreme Ct, NY State: Affidavits; Progress Reports - 1st, 2nd, 3rd, 1989 September 29-1989 October 24 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Application for Wiretaps; 5th, 6th and 7th Progress Reports, 1989 October 30-1989 November 21 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Supreme Court, NY State: Application for Wiretaps; 9th 7 10th Progress Reports, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Supreme Court, NY State: Affidavit in Support of Wiretap, 1989 December 20 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Supreme Ct, NY State: 29th, 30th, 32nd, 34th Progress Reports; Affidavits, undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Affidavits; 35th, 36th and 38th Progress Reports, 1990 January 16-1990 February 27 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - People v. Capaldo, Kamen, et. al. and People v. S. Strelzik - Indictments, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Affidavit in Support of Wiretaps; 12th, 13th, 15th-17th Progress Reports, undated (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Supreme Court, NY State: Affidavit; 19th Progress Report, 1990 February 5-1990 February 20 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - District Attorney's Office: Press Release (Indictment), 1990 June 21 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Painters Free Press: Trusteeship (flyers; proposals; Special Trusteeship), 1977 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Trusteeship: John Alfarone: Correspondence; Flyers; Press; Notes: F. Schonfeld, 1989-1994 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Legal Correspondence, etc. DC 9; F.S.; Indexes, 1962-1972 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Yochim, Wm. v. Caputo, L., Rarback, M., 1962 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Salzhandler, S. (Free Speech of Union Members, B. Hall), 1963, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Painting Industry Insurance Fund, 1909-1992 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Buffalo Trusteeship (Wolford; Dunlop), 1964-1986 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Indictment: Glaziers Local, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Rarback, M.: Indictment (F. Hogan), 1966 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Trusteeship Hearing: Exhibits; Testimony of F. S., 1966-1967 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - U.S. Dist. Court: Court Of Appeals: Schonfeld v. Rarback: Briefs; Law Text, 1962-1972 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - U.S. Dist. Court Fritsch and Rossiter v. DC 9; Schonfeld v. Raftery, 1967-1974 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Schonfeld v. Raftery: Briefs, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Schonfeld v. Raftery: Brief for Appellants (Vladeck, et. al.), undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Schonfeld v. Raftery: Appellee's Brief (B. Hall), undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Schonfeld v. Raftery: Briefs, 1967-1973, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Schonfeld v. Raftery; Fritsch and Rossiter v. DC 9: Transcripts, 1972 July 5 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Schonfeld v. Raftery; Fritsch and Rossiter v. DC 9 Transcripts, 1972 July 27 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Schonfeld v. Raftery; Fritsch et. al. v. DC 9: Transcripts, 1972 July 28 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - People of State of NY v. M. Rarback (Plea), 1973 October 31 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Giraldo, Al and IBPAT v. Rosen, S., Schonfeld, F. (Staff Pension Plan), 1972 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Supreme Court, NY State: Blackman and Siegel v. Schonfeld, 1969-1972 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Schonfeld v. Penza, 197 May 5-1972 September 15 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Schonfeld v. Penza, 1972 May-1972 November (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - U.S. Court of Appeals - Schonfeld v. Penza (Briefs), 1972 December-1973 April (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Schonfeld v. Penza; Schwartz v. DC 9, 1972-1974 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Hearing; U.S. Court of Appeals (Painters Section), 1974 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - U.S. District Court - IBPAT v. DC 9 (Trusteeship), 1977 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Al Herman, Charles Siegel v. Painting Industry Insurance Fund, 1977-1981 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Arnold, F. v. DC 9 and IBPAT, 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Schonfeld v. Local 19, 1980-1983 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - U.S. District Court, Schonfeld et al. v. Bishop, J., Nochese, T., 1980 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - U.S. District Court v. Corrado (Dino) Marino, 1982 March-1982 June (Box 7, Folder 33)
- Series VII: Internal Trials, 1927-1979
  Includes cases involving employers as parties to the Master Painters and Master Contractors Association in regard to violations of the collective bargaining agreement.
  - Executive Trial Board v. Schonfeld - #1, 1972 May 3 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Ex. Trial Bd. v. Schonfeld: #2, 1972 May 3 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Ex. Trial Bd. v. Schonfeld: #3, 1972 May 4 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Ex. Trial Bd. v. Schonfeld: #4, 1972 May 6 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Ex. Trial Bd. v. Schonfeld: #5, 1972 May 13 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Ex. Trial Bd. v. Schonfeld: #6, 1972 May 17 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Ex. Trial Bd. v. Schonfeld: #7, 1972 May 20 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Ex. Trial Bd. v. Schonfeld: #8 (afternoon session), 1972 May 20 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Ex. Trial Bd. v. Schonfeld: #9, 1972 May 24 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Ex. Trial Bd. v. Schonfeld: #10, 1972 May 25 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Ex. Trial Bd. v. Schonfeld: #11, 1972 May 31 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Ex. Trial Bd. v. Schonfeld: #12, 1972 June 7 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Ex. Trial Bd. v. Schonfeld: #13, 1972 June 13 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Ex. Trial Bd. v. Schonfeld: #14, 1972 June 14 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Ex. Trial Bd. v. Schonfeld: #15, 1972 June 15 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Ex. Trial Bd. v. Schonfeld: #16, 1972 June 21 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Ex. Trial Bd. v. Schonfeld: #17, 1972 June 22 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Ex. Trial Bd. v. Schonfeld: #18, 1972 June 24 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Ex. Trial Bd. v. Schonfeld: #19, 1972 June 28 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Ex. Trial Bd. v. Schonfeld: #20, 1972 June 29 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Ex. Trial Bd. v. Schonfeld: #21, 1972 July 5 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Ex. Trial Bd. v. Schonfeld: #22, 1972 July 6 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Ex. Trial Bd. v. Schonfeld: #23, 1972 July 12 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Ex. Trial Bd. v. Schonfeld: #24, 1972 July 13 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Ex. Trial Bd. v. Schonfeld: #25, 1972 July 19 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Ex. Trial Bd. v. Schonfeld: #26, 1972 August 9 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Ex. Trial Bd. v. Schonfeld: #27, 1972 August 23 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Ex. Trial Bd. v. Schonfeld: #28, 1972 August 24 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Ex. Trial Bd. v. Schonfeld: #29, 1972 August 28 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Ex. Trial Bd. v. Schonfeld: #30, 1972 August 29 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Ex. Trial Bd. v. Schonfeld: #31, 1972 August 30 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Ex. Trial Bd. Schonfeld v. Penza (Brief; Exhibits etc.), 1970-1973 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Ex. Trial Board: Appeal, F. Schonfeld etc., 1972 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - DC 9 Trial Committee: Local 51 v. Thomas Wright (1 of 4), 1927 July 9 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Local 51 v. T. Wright (#2 of 4), 1927 July 9 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Local 51 v. T. Wright (#3 of 4), 1927 July 9 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Local 51 v. T. Wright (#4 of 4), 1927 July 9 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - DC 9 Trial Bd. v. Louis Weinstock: Transcript, 1944 February 7 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Trial Bd.: Minutes of Meeting on Charges v. Ralph French, 1947 September 9 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Trial Bd. v. L. Weinstock (C.P. Membership), undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Trial Bd. Hearing: Morris Davis: L.U. #848, 1947-1948 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Trial Bd.: Rarback v. Davis, 1948 November 6 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Trial Bd.: Rarback v. Mandel (Report of Trial Committee), 1949 April 28 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Trial Bd.: Charges v. Ben Richman (L. U. #1011), 1960 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Hearings: Local #121; Local #1511: in re DC 9 Affiliation, 1961 September (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Trial Bd.: Rarback v. Yochim, et al, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Trial Committee: Rarback Slander Case, 1961, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Trial and Appeal of F. Schonfeld: Correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Appeal: F. Schonfeld, Wm. Yochim and Local #905, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Trial Bd.: Guinta v. Topp, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - H. Robbins, Local #892: Charges on Financial Mismanagement, 1967-1969 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Chicago: Charges v. Wally St. Martin, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Hubbard Painting and Contracting: Arbitrations, 1973 April (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Midland Painting and Spec Painting and Decorating v. DC 9: NLRB, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - John Lekas v. Ebony Painting Co. and Estimating Service Co., 1976-1977 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Morgan Post Office: Ben Strauss Industries (F. Schonfeld, Charges), 1978 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Trade Bd. Cases (Lists; Pending; Pacific Painting; NY Tel.), 1971-1976 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Amalgamated Housing (J. Bishop v. F. Schonfeld) Agreement; Correspondence, etc., 1977-1980 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Trial and Appeal of F. Schonfeld, 1972-1979 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Internal Trials: Schonfeld (Transcripts; Inc.), undated (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - A. Dixon; Petition to Master Painters, NYC, Against Judgment, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - J and M Gonzalez Painting Co.; DC 9 and 32B-32J: Stipulation and Order; NLRB, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 26)
- Series VIII: Insurance Funds, 1938-1994
  Includes minutes of meetings of the board of trustees and related materials, including reports and publicity prepared by the opposition in efforts to expose the corrupt activities of the Fund managers. Simon Kesselman's correspondence, centering on mismanagement of the Painters annuity funds, illustrates the issues that fueled members' staunch opposition to the District leadership.
  - Insurance, Pension and Annuity Funds: Minutes of Trustees Meetings, 1967-1968 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Trustees Meetings: Minutes, 1968-1969 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Trustees Meetings: Minutes, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Trustees Meetings: Minutes, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Trustees Meetings: Minutes, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Trustees Meetings: Minutes, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Trustees Meetings: Minutes, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Trustees Meetings: Minutes, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Trustees Meetings: Minutes, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Delinquency Letters, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Trustees Meetings: Minutes, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Trustees Meetings: Minutes, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Trustees Meetings: Minutes, 1977-1978 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Trustees Meetings: Minutes, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Blank Forms; Accounting, Insurance Funds, undated (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Joint Industry Bd.: Correspondence, Forms, Notes, 1969-1978 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Insurance Funds: Correspondence, 1946-1992 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Insurance Funds: Meetings (Trustees; Others), 1968-1979 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Insurance Funds: Financial Statements, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Welfare, Annuity and Pension Funds: Financial Records, 1970-1978 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Insurance, Annuity and Pension Funds: Manuel Rarback, 1975-1976 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - United Coalition of Painters and Allied Trades: Bank Statements, etc., 1976-1977 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Insurance, Annuity and Pension Funds: Stewards Reports; Delinquencies, etc., undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Sam Lemkin (Charges; Pension), 1949, 1974-1975 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Insurance Funds Scandal: An Unsigned Account; Strauss, Bishop, Arnold, 1970s (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Joint Trade Committee: Ahern; Marke; Small, 1978-1979 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Insurance Funds: Press Clippings; Flyers, 1948-1994, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Insurance Funds: Notes of F. Schonfeld, 1965-1981, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Fund Information and Retrieval System, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Insurance Fund: Testimonial Letters in re: H.I.P., undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Local 442: Simon Kesselman: Correspondence (Insurance Fund Fraud, etc.), 1938-1961 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - S. Kesselman: Correspondence, 1962-1963 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - S. Kesselman: Correspondence, 1963-1965 (Box 10, Folder 18)
- Series IX: Subject Files, 1940-1981
  Contains materials relating to the amalgamation of locals, the effort to establish a separate local for Civil Service Painters (Local 1969) and Tapers (Local 1974), and a failed attempt to set up a Florida retirement community, Holiday Park, in addition to documentation of mass meetings, co-op activity, and health hazards for painters.
  - Anti-Semitism (Articles), 1962 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Building Trades Employers Association, 1947-1972 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Civil Service Local: Local 1969: Petition Campaign (Wm. Papson), 1966 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Civil Service Local 1969: By-Laws; Press Release, etc. (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Civil Service Local 1969: Correspondence; Flyers; Election Materials, 1969-1977 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Civil Service Local v. Local 237, IBT, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Civil Service Local 1969: Accounts, 1973-1977 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Civil Service Local 1969: Prevailing Wage Campaign (Notes), 1974-1977 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Civil Rights: AFL-CIO; DC 9, 1969-1971 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Consolidation of DC 9 into One Local Union (Argument), 1942 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Co-Op City; United Housing Foundation, undated (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Cooperatives, 1943-1952 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Corruption in Construction (Public Meeting: Program), 1991 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - District Council 9: "Work for Victory Day", 1941-1945 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Hardwood Finishers (Trade Agreement; Jurisdictional Dispute with Carpenters (See also Santos, F.), 1965-1969 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Health Hazards: Painting Industry, 1967-1981 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Holiday Park Retirement Community, FL (IBPAT), 1975-1977 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Housing and Urban Development, U.S. Dept. of (Opposition to DC 9 Agreement), 1976-1977 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - League for Industrial Democracy (Summer Labor Institute), 1967 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Lemkin, Sam, 1946, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Liberal Party, undated (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Mass Meetings: Louis Weinstock, circa 1948 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Mass Meetings: Frank Schonfeld, 1961-1974 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Minneapolis 18: Correspondence in Support; Press; Petitions, 1943-1951 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - New York City Board of Education: Painting Contracts, etc., 1961-1979 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - New York City Housing Authority, 1967-1971 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - New York City: Re-Painting (Apartments; DC 9), 1940-1959 (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Office of Labor Racketeering / NY State O.C.T.F. - Report, 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - Paperhangers Local 490: "Roots of Local Union 490 from the Official Minutes" (typescript), undated (Box 10, Folder 46A)
  - Reform Politics: Bronx, NY, 1940-1969 (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - Seniority: Affirmative Action Debate (Al Nash), undated (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - Tapers: Petition for Separate Local, DC 9 (i.e., Local 1974), 1968 (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - Tapers: Jurisdictional Dispute, DC 9, 1971-1972 (Box 10, Folder 50)
- Series X: Election Records, 1934-1992
  Includes materials related to the contentious atmosphere that pervaded relations between District Council 9 and its many locals. Disagreements often reflect the three major factions in the union, the Progressives, the Rank-and-File, and the reform platform organized by Frank Schonfeld.
  - United Painters Rank and File Committee of DC 9, 1935-1950 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Inter Local Progressive Clubs of New York, 1938-1951 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Inter Local Club of Progressive Painters - Minutes, 1938-1949 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Inter Local Club of Progressive Painters - Yiddish Flyers, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Weinstock, Louis: Election, 1942, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Progressive Painters of DC 9, 1938-1949 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - United Active Painters, 1940s (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - District 9 Elections: Progressives v. Rank-and-File, 1946 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Martin Rarback Election, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Communist Party: Painters Branch, 1946-1950 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Louis Weinstock: Rank-and-File Election Materials, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Local 261: Painters Democratic Club (Rank-and-File), undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Local 442 (Weinstock), 1938-1946 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Election Materials: Rank-and-File: Local 848, 1947-1948 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Local 848: Anti-Weinstock Materials, undated (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Rank-and-File Club: Local 892, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Local 905: Rank-and-File, 1947 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Local 905: Anti-Weinstock Material, undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Morris Davis, Secretary, Local 848: "I Refuse to be Gagged", 1949-1950 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Reports, Local 848, 1949 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Election Materials: Rank-and-File; Progressives, etc., 1948, 1967-1973 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Bulletins; Election etc. Materials (Various Tendencies), 1948-1973 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Local 806 (Bridge Painters): Jurisdiction Dispute/Bishop Anti-Schonfeld, 1969-1976 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - James Bishop: Campaign Materials, 1970-1973 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Schonfeld-Bishop Campaign, circa 1973-1976 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Thomas Nochese: Election Materials, 1940s (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Local 1011: Election Materials; Notes, 1934, 1942-1976 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Local 1011: Election (H. Rubenstein), 1943 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Local 1011: Campaign Flyers, 1949-1977 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Local 1011: Election Appeal, 1961 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Frank P. Loria: Campaign Flyers; Newsletters; Petitions, 1964-1973 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Local 1507, 1511 (Brooklyn) Campaign Flyers, 1966 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Election Flyers, 1940-1969 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Election Flyers, 1970-1992 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Election Flyers, undated (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Election Complaints; Correspondence (DoL etc.), 1961-1976 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Sample Ballots; Tallies etc., 1964-1985 (Box 11, Folder 37)
- Series XI: Rank-and-File Groups, 1961-1980
  Includes materials from various rank-and-file groups, mostly reflecting efforts spearheaded by Schonfeld.
  - United Committee for Democracy in DC 9, 1961-1965 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Painters Free Press: Bulletins, 1961-1965 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Painters Free Press: Bulletins, 1966-1974 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Painters Free Press: Bulletins, 1975-1980 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Labor Committee Against Corruption in the Painting Industry: Corr., 1964-1967 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Labor Committee: Press; Flyers, 1965-1967 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Labor Committee: Press Releases, 1965-1967 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Labor Committee: Charges; Resolutions; Proposals, 1965-1966 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Labor Committee's Proposal to AFL-CIO in re Corruption in IBPAT, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Labor Committee: Legal Texts; Notes, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Labor Committee: Notes (F. Schonfeld), undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Membership Rights Club (founded by Painters Free Press / F.S.) Bulletins, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Washington DC E. Mann / Painters Clean up Club - Local 1011, 1963-1967 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Active Painters Club: Local 1011, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Progressive Painter: Local 1011 Extra, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 15)
- Series XII: California Painters, 1961-1977
  Includes documentation on Dow Wilson's leadership in Painters Local 4, the strike he conducted, the campaign against him, and the murders and subsequent resolutions in tribute to him. The series also includes correspondence between Schonfeld and Wilson, documenting their mutual attempts to interest the leadership of the Painters Union and the AFL-CIO in a clean-up campaign.
  - San Francisco: Local 4 (Correspondence; Dow Wilson / F. Schonfeld, 1965-1972 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Frank Schonfeld: Notes / CA, undated (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Local 4: Letters to the Membership, 1966, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Grievances; Complaints" CA, 1963-1966 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, Strike: Local 4 (Notes), 1965 June-1965 October (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: Contractors: Strike, Local 4 (NLRB, etc.), 1965 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Clippings, Local 4 Strike, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Minutes: Painters, CA, 1961-1967 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - DC 8, Northern CA: Charges Against Dow Wilson, 1965 March-1965 November (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Letters in Support of Dow Wilson, 1965 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Resolutions: Dow Wilson, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - New York: Resolutions, Correspondence, in re Dow Wilson's Murder, 1966 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Clippings: Dow Wilson, undated (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Union Painters Bulletin (San Francisco), 1974 July 30 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - By-Laws; Resolutions: CA Painters, undated (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Collective Bargaining Agreements: CA, 1962-1970 (Box 12, Folder 31)
- Series XIII: Clippings, 1946-1992
  Contains articles related to activities within the District Council.
  - New York City: DC 9: Press Clippings, 1947-1992 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - Building Service Union: 32B, 1954-1966 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Press Clippings; Labor, Construction, Corruption, 1946-1985 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Press Clippings; Labor, Construction, etc., undated (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Yiddish Press: Translations, 1961-1972 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Yiddish Press: DC 9, 1957-1973 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Italian Press Clip, undated (Box 12, Folder 38)
- Series XIV: By-Laws, 1960-1993